<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BuildingBlocksHR</string>
    <string name="open">open</string>
    <string name="close">close</string>
    <string name="hrHelpTitle">How to use the App</string>
    <string name="helpMsg">Instructions on how to use the App go here!</string>
    <string name="OkMsg">Got it!</string>
    <string name="policy"><u>Policies      </u></string>
    <string name="compliance">Compliance Policies</string>
    <string name="violance_harassment">Viloence, Workplace and Sexual Harassment</string>
    <string name="aoda">AODA</string>
    <string name="health_safety">Health and Safety</string>
    <string name="privacy">Privacy and Personal information</string>
    <string name="other_policies">Other Policies</string>
    <string name="vacation">Vacation</string>
    <string name="benefits">Benefits</string>
    <string name="loading">Just a moment...</string>
    <string name="violence_policy_heading"><u>Violence in the Workplace Policy</u></string>
    <string name="scope_heading">Applicability and Scope</string>
    <string name="scope">This policy applies to all the company employees, including temporary employees and independent contractors.</string>
    <string name="scope_applicable">The policy is applicable whenever an employee or independent contractor:</string>
    <string name="p1bullet1">\u2022,Carries out duties or conducts business on behalf of the company;</string>
    <string name="p1bullet2">•, Represents the company on committees or at work related events/conferences</string>
    <string name="p1bullet3">•, Attends work-related and industry functions; and/or</string>
    <string name="p1bullet4">•, Socializes with other employees.</string>
    <string name="scope_location"> Locations and situations covered by this policy include, but are not limited to:</string>
    <string name="location_bullet1">•, the company offices and worksites;</string>
    <string name="location_bullet2">•, Other buildings or premises under the jurisdiction of the company;</string>
    <string name="location_bullet3">•, Company vehicles;</string>
    <string name="location_bullet4">•, Social functions sanctioned by or under the jurisdiction of the company whether held at company offices or facilities or at other locations approved by the company;</string>
    <string name="location_bullet5">•, Work-related travel outside of company facilities;</string>
    <string name="location_bullet6">•, Incidents which occur outside the workplace, but have negative repercussions at work or adversely affect working relationships;</string>
    <string name="location_bullet7">" •, Harassment that occurs by electronic means (e-mail, telephone, voice mail, internet, or fax) or written communication; and"</string>
    <string name="location_bullet8">•, Any other locations or events where company business, operations, or social functions are carried out.</string>
    <string name="policyIntent_heading">Policy Intent</string>
    <string name="intentp1">The company recognizes that every person is entitled to a safe work environment that is free of violence and threatening behaviour.</string>
    <string name="intentp2">The company will adhere to the spirit and intent of all applicable federal and provincial legislation governing workplace violence including, but not limited to, the Occupational Health and Safety Act, the Criminal Code, and Bill 168, etc.</string>
    <string name="intentp3">The company is committed to maintaining a workplace where all employees are treated with dignity and respect. There will be zero tolerance of any form of workplace violence or threatening behaviour toward its employees.</string>
    <string name="intentp4">Specifically, if the company is aware that domestic violence is likely to expose an employee to a workplace physical injury, every reasonable precaution will be implemented to protect the individual.</string>
    <string name="intentp5">The company will also disclose information about anyone who has a history of violent behaviour to employee(s) who may come in contact with that person.</string>
    <string name="intentp6">It is a violation of the company’s Violence in the Workplace Policy for anyone to knowingly make a false complaint of violence, or to provide false information about a complaint. Individuals who violate this Policy are subject to disciplinary and/or corrective action, up to and including termination of employment</string>
    <string name="intentp7">This policy outlines the commitment, principles and procedures that the company will follow with respect to preventing and stopping violence in the workplace.</string>
    <string name="purpose_heading">Purpose</string>
    <string name="purpose_p1">The purpose of this policy is to provide information to all employees regarding:</string>
    <string name="purpose_bullet1">•, Workplace Violence</string>
    <string name="purpose_bullet2">•, Handling Complaints</string>
    <string name="accountability_heading">Accountability</string>
    <string name="accountability_p1">The company will, in accordance with all provincial legislation and Occupational Health and Safety Act:</string>
    <string name="account_bullet1">•, Appoint a Workplace Violence and Harassment Coordinator;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet2">•, Assess the risk of workplace violence that may result from the nature of the company worksites and the nature and conditions of work performed there;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet3">•, Establish and maintain procedures to control the risks identified in the risk assessment;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet4">•, Reassess the risk of workplace violence as often as is necessary;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet5">•, Take every reasonable precaution to protect employees from domestic violence that may occur in the workplace and expose employees to physical injury;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet6">•, Establish measures for summoning immediate assistance when workplace violence is threatened, occurs, or is likely to occur;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet7">•, Inform employees on when and how to seek medical assistance should a violent incident occur in the workplace;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet8">•, Establish a reporting procedure for incidents or threats of workplace violence;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet9">•, Establish an investigation procedure for dealing with incidents or allegations of workplace violence or threats of violence;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet10">•, Provide all employees with training and information regarding this policy and associated procedures;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet11">•, Monitor the company compliance with this policy and established procedures;</string>
    <string name="account_bullet12">•, Review this policy annually to ensure that it is current and effective.</string>
    <string name="accountability_p2">Accountability for ensuring compliance with the provisions of this policy rests with Management.</string>


</resources>