<resources>

    <string name="register">No account? Register <font color='#01C6DB'>here.</font></string>
    <string name="app_name">BuildingBlocksHR</string>
    <string name="open">open</string>
    <string name="close">close</string>
    <string name="hrHelpTitle">How to use the App</string>
    <string name="helpMsg">Instructions on how to use the App go here!</string>
    <string name="OkMsg">Got it!</string>
    <string name="policy"><u>Policies      </u></string>
    <string name="compliance">Compliance Policies</string>
    <string name="violance_harassment">Viloence, Workplace and Sexual Harassment</string>
    <string name="aoda">AODA</string>
    <string name="health_safety">Health and Safety</string>
    <string name="privacy">Privacy and Personal information</string>
    <string name="other_policies">Other Policies</string>
    <string name="vacation"><u>Vacation</u></string>
    <string name="benefits"><u>Benefits</u></string>
    <string name="loading">Just a moment...</string>
    <string name="violence_policy_heading"><u>Violence in the Workplace Policy</u></string>
    <string name="scope_heading">Applicability and Scope</string>
    <string name="scope">This policy applies to all the company employees, including temporary employees and independent contractors.</string>
    <string name="scope_applicable">The policy is applicable whenever an employee or independent contractor:</string>
    <string name="p1bullet1">\u2022,Carries out duties or conducts business on behalf of the company;
        \n• Represents the company on committees or at work related events/conferences
        \n• Attends work-related and industry functions; and/or
        \n• Socializes with other employees.</string>

    <string name="scope_location"> Locations and situations covered by this policy include, but are not limited to:</string>
    <string name="location_bullet1">• the company offices and worksites;
        \n• Other buildings or premises under the jurisdiction of the company;
        \n• Company vehicles;
        \n• Social functions sanctioned by or under the jurisdiction of the company whether held at company offices or facilities or at other locations approved by the company;
        \n• Work-related travel outside of company facilities;
        \n• Incidents which occur outside the workplace, but have negative repercussions at work or adversely affect working relationships;
        \n• Harassment that occurs by electronic means (e-mail, telephone, voice mail, internet, or fax) or written communication; and
        \n• Any other locations or events where company business, operations, or social functions are carried out.</string>

    <string name="policyIntent_heading">Policy Intent</string>
    <string name="intentp1">The company recognizes that every person is entitled to a safe work environment that is free of violence and threatening behaviour.</string>
    <string name="intentp2">The company will adhere to the spirit and intent of all applicable federal and provincial legislation governing workplace violence including, but not limited to, the Occupational Health and Safety Act, the Criminal Code, and Bill 168, etc.</string>
    <string name="intentp3">The company is committed to maintaining a workplace where all employees are treated with dignity and respect. There will be zero tolerance of any form of workplace violence or threatening behaviour toward its employees.</string>
    <string name="intentp4">Specifically, if the company is aware that domestic violence is likely to expose an employee to a workplace physical injury, every reasonable precaution will be implemented to protect the individual.</string>
    <string name="intentp5">The company will also disclose information about anyone who has a history of violent behaviour to employee(s) who may come in contact with that person.</string>
    <string name="intentp6">It is a violation of the company’s Violence in the Workplace Policy for anyone to knowingly make a false complaint of violence, or to provide false information about a complaint. Individuals who violate this Policy are subject to disciplinary and/or corrective action, up to and including termination of employment</string>
    <string name="intentp7">This policy outlines the commitment, principles and procedures that the company will follow with respect to preventing and stopping violence in the workplace.</string>
    <string name="purpose_heading">Purpose</string>
    <string name="purpose_p1">The purpose of this policy is to provide information to all employees regarding:</string>
    <string name="purpose_bullet1">• Workplace Violence
        \n• Handling Complaints </string>

    <string name="accountability_heading">Accountability</string>
    <string name="accountability_p1">The company will, in accordance with all provincial legislation and Occupational Health and Safety Act:</string>
    <string name="account_bullet1">• Appoint a Workplace Violence and Harassment Coordinator;
        \n• Assess the risk of workplace violence that may result from the nature of the company worksites and the nature and conditions of work performed there;
        \n• Establish and maintain procedures to control the risks identified in the risk assessment;
        \n• Reassess the risk of workplace violence as often as is necessary;
        \n• Take every reasonable precaution to protect employees from domestic violence that may occur in the workplace and expose employees to physical injury;
        \n• Establish measures for summoning immediate assistance when workplace violence is threatened, occurs, or is likely to occur;
        \n• Inform employees on when and how to seek medical assistance should a violent incident occur in the workplace;
        \n\u2022 Establish an investigation procedure for dealing with incidents or allegations of workplace violence or threats of violence;
        \n• Provide all employees with training and information regarding this policy and associated procedures;
        \n• Monitor the company compliance with this policy and established procedures;  </string>
    <string name="account_bullet12">• Review this policy annually to ensure that it is current and effective.</string>

    <string name="accountability_p2">Accountability for ensuring compliance with the provisions of this policy rests with Management.</string>
    <string name="account_responsibilities">Responsibilities of Employees:</string>
    <string name="responsibilities_bullet1">• Familiarize themselves with this policy;
        \n• Attend any training related to this policy;
        \n• Ask their supervisor for clarification on this policy if they have questions;
        \n• Help promote a violence-free workplace;
        \n• Refrain from workplace violence as defined in this policy; and
        \n• Immediately report to appropriate management staff incidents of, threats of, or potential for workplace violence, whether directly experienced or witnessed.</string>

    <string name="account_management">Responsibilities of Management:</string>
    <string name="management_bullet1">\u2022 Foster a violence-free workplace;
        \n• Ensure that employees receive adequate information and training on this policy;
        \n• Report any incidents or potential for workplace violence;
        \n• Investigate all aspects of any reported instances of harassment in conjunction with reporting in a timely manner;
        \n• Maintain confidentiality in the investigation process;
        \n• If a member of management becomes aware or receives knowledge that:</string>

    <string name="management_bullet6i">i.  Domestic violence may occur in the workplace that would likely expose any employee to physical injury;
        \n ii.  An employee may, in the course of their duties, encounter another employee or other person who has a history of violent behaviour, and
        \n iii.  There is a risk of workplace violence that is likely to expose the employee to physical injury.</string>

    <string name="management_responsibilities">Management will immediately advise who will provide information, including personal information, to the employee sufficient to protect them from physical injury. Personal information will only be provided that is reasonably necessary to protect the employee from physical injury.</string>
    <string name="violence_workplace_heading">Violence in the Workplace</string>
    <string name="violence_intro">Violence in the workplace involves the infliction of physical and/or mental injuries by an individual or individuals, whether employed or not employed by the company. The company prohibits any type of violence in the work environment and employees who exhibit workplace violence will be subject to disciplinary action up to and including termination of employment.</string>
    <string name="violence_def">\"Workplace violence\" means but not limited to:</string>
    <string name="violence_def_bullet1">• The exercise of physical force against an employee in a workplace that causes, or could cause, physical injury to the employee, their personal property, their family, or their friends;
        \n• An attempt to exercise physical force against an employee in a workplace that could cause physical injury to the employee, their personal property, their family, or their friends;
        \n• A statement or behaviour that is reasonable for an employee to interpret as a threat to exercise physical force against an employee, in a workplace, that causes or could cause physical injury to the employee;
        \n• Physical acts (e.g. hitting, shoving, pushing, kicking, sexual assault);
        \n• Any threat, behaviour or action which is interpreted to carry the potential to harm or endanger the safety of others, result in an act of aggression, or destroy or damage property;
        \n• Disruptive behaviour that is not appropriate to the work environment (e.g. yelling, swearing);
        \n• Any such actions which occur outside the workplace, but have repercussions in the work environment. </string>

    <string name="violence_example">Examples of workplace violence include, but are not limited to:</string>
    <string name="violence_ex_bullet1">• Allowing or engaging in violent events/behaviour and threats verbal or written or physical gestures;
        \n• Harassing phone calls, voicemails or e-mail messages;
        \n• Having/threatening with a weapon;
        \n• Offensive comments;
        \n• Physical assault.</string>

    <string name="weapons_example">Examples of Weapons include, but are not limited to:</string>
    <string name="weapons_ex_bullet1">• Dangerous chemicals other than mace or pepper spray;
       \n• Firearms;
       \n• Knives with a blade length of 3.5 inches or greater.</string>

    <string name="prevention_guidelines">The following are some general guidelines for helping to prevent violence in the workplace:</string>
    <string name="prevention_bullet1">• Do not personalize the words or actions (i.e.: don’t get defensive and don’t feed into their anger);
        \n• Stick to the issues or facts of the situation;
        \n• Be polite and professional;
        \n• Try to paraphrase the other party’s concerns back to them, to let them know that they are being heard and understood;
        \n• Do not attempt to physically touch the other party;
        \n• Report, record and investigate all incidents of violence;
        \n• If an employee has been the victim of violence in the workplace, be sure to complete and submit a report (within 24 hours of occurrence), so that this individual can receive appropriate counselling.</string>

    <string name="incident_report">In the event that an employee is either directly affected by or witness to any violence in the workplace, it is imperative for the safety of all the company employees that the incident be reported without delay.</string>
    <string name="incident_report_bullet1">• Report any violence or potentially violent situations immediately to management;
        \n• Depending on the severity of the situation, the local police may be called;
        \n• All reports shall be kept confidential;
        \n• All reports shall be investigated, and dealt with appropriately;
        \n• Any the company employee who threatens, harasses or abuses another employee, or any other individual at or from the workplace shall be subject to disciplinary action, up to and including termination of employment,
        and the pursuit of appropriate legal action;
        \n• Violent action, threats and assault are serious criminal offences, and shall be dealt with appropriately.</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step1">Step 1</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_p1">Any person who feels that he/she has experienced workplace violence or threats of such violence may request assistance or file a complaint under this policy without prejudice or fear of reprisal. If you believe that you have been threatened with or subjected to workplace violence:</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_heading">Reporting and Investigating Complaints of Violence in the Workplace</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_bullet1">• If you believe that an employee or other person with whom you interact in the course of your duties (for example, a customer, supplier, etc.) has subjected you to violence or threats of violence, report the incident to management immediately.
        \n• Keep a record of the incident(s) including dates, location, witnesses, your response to the individual and any other pertinent information.
        \n• If allegations of workplace violence are made against you, keep a record of your version of the alleged incident. If you believe the complaint is unfounded or made in bad faith, discuss the matter with management immediate.</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step2">Step 2</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step2_bullet1">• If the offensive behaviour does not stop, file a formal written complaint to management. Any formal written complaint filed by an employee must contain:</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step2_bullet1_2">• Name(s) of the respondent(s);
        \n• The date or dates of the incident(s);
        \n• Location(s) of the alleged incident(s);
        \n• Details of the incident(s); and
        \n• Names of any witnesses.</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step2_bullet2">• The issue will be addressed with the alleged offender in accordance with Step 3.</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step3">Step 3</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step3_bullet1">• The written complaint will be reviewed and may determine that an investigation is warranted and evidence indicates that violence, as defined by the policy and applicable legislation, has occurred.
        \n• Measures will be implemented immediately to protect the victim from further harm.
        \n• Confidentiality will be maintained at all times except when the disclosure of names is necessary for the purpose of investigating the complaint, when taking any action in relation to the complaint, or where disclosure is required by law.
        \n•  If criminal actions are alleged, witnessed, or found to have occurred, the appropriate member of management will contact Law enforcement agency immediately. Criminal actions include, but are not limited to, the following behaviours:</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step3_bullet1_2">• The displaying of hate-based graffiti or pornography;
        \n\u2022 The transmission or storing of electronic telecommunications that incite hatred and violence or that constitute pornography;
        \n▪ The displaying of symbols or emblems (including clothing) that suggest racial supremacy and incite hatred and violence;
        \n▪ Stalking (persistently pursuing a particular individual although the advances are clearly unwelcome);
        \n▪ Sexual assault or threat of sexual assault;
        \n▪ Threats against an individual or their loved ones or family;
        \n▪ Extortion; and/ or
        \n▪ Physical assault or threats of physical assault.</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_note">Note: Whether or not a formal complaint is filed, the company or a third party may be obligated to proceed with an investigation if it appears that applicable legislation and/or the policy has been violated.</string>
    <string name="sexual_harassment_heading">Workplace Harassment Policy</string>
    <string name="aoda_heading">Accessibility Standard for Customer Service AODA Policy </string>
    <string name="health_safety_heading">Health and Safety Policy</string>
    <string name="applicability_heading">Applicability</string>
    <string name="health_intent_p1">The policy intent is to ensure that the company commitment to providing a healthy and safe work environment is communicated and understood by all employees.
        \n\nThe company (the “Company”) considers health and safety a critical priority requiring the constant attention and involvement of both management and employees. The company requires that
        all employees comply with all applicable health and safety regulations and insists that all employees respect and abide by spirit and intent of health and safety regulations.
        \n\nA healthy and safe workplace benefits both the company and its employees.  Management and employees have a shared responsibility to maintain a healthy and safe workplace.  Management is
        committed to promoting safe work practices and to taking all reasonable precautions to address workplace hazards.  Employees will accept responsibility for working in a safe manner and for
        bringing potentially hazardous conditions or practices to the attention of management.
        \n\nIt is the company’s policy to:
        \n\n(a) Strive toward eliminating workplace injuries and illnesses.
        \n(b) Have a fire safety and emergency plan in place.
        \n(c) Comply with municipal, provincial and federal health and safety legislation.</string>

    <string name="privacy_heading">Privacy and Personal Infromation and Electronic Documents Policy</string>
    <string name="applicability_p1">These guidelines apply to all the company employees, including temporary employees.</string>
    <string name="privacy_intent_p1">The company is committed to protecting the privacy of personal information of its clients, employees, independent contractors, funders and other stakeholders.  the company corporate policy on privacy is posted on the Company website at www.motionspecialties.com.
        \n\nEmployees’ personal information remains confidential throughout their career as well as after their employment with the company ends. Employees’ information will not be collected used or disclosed except in accordance with the guidelines of federal and provincial privacy acts.  Information
        about any employee will not be released without the employee’s authorization except where required by law.
        \n\nThe company will only collect employees’ personal information where permission is provided or if there is a potential contravention of the law or breaches of agreements or other circumstances that permit us to legally collect this information under the laws of Canada.
        \n\nThis policy is to ensure that the company is complying with the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA) that outlines the protection for an employee in regards to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information </string>
    <string name="aoda_p1">The Accessibility Standard for Customer Service is an Ontario regulation that applies to all people and organizations across all provinces where the company operates. "</string>
    <string name="aoda_intent_p1">The purpose of this policy is to ensure that the company is committed to excellence in serving all clients including individuals with disabilities.</string>
    <string name="regulation_heading">The Regulation</string>
    <string name="aoda_regualtion_p1">Recognizing the history of discrimination against persons with disabilities in Ontario and Canada, the purpose of the Accessibility Standard for Customer Service is to benefit everyone by:
        \n\n(a) Developing, implementing and enforcing accessibility standards in order to achieve accessibility for Ontarians with disabilities with respect to goods, services, facilities, accommodation, employment, buildings, structures and premises on or before January 1, 2012; and
        \n\n(b) Providing for the involvement of persons with disabilities, of all the Governments and of representatives of industries and of various sectors of the economy in the development of the accessibility standards. </string>

    <string name="responsibilities_heading">Responsibilities</string>
    <string name="responsibilities_p1">All the company employees have a responsibility not to harass any other employee, contract employee, consultant, supplier, customer or visitor. Each employee in a management capacity must not allow or condone behaviour contrary to this policy and is
        responsible for ensuring that all employees under his or her supervision are aware of this policy. Any employee who fails to comply with the provisions of this policy will be subject to appropriate disciplinary measures, which may include termination.</string>
    <string name="employer_procedure_heading">Employers – Procedure for Handling Complaints</string>
    <string name="formal_investigation_heading">FORMAL INVESTIGATION PROCEDURE</string>
    <string name="investigation_p1">1. A designated investigator will undertake an investigation immediately and all necessary steps will be taken to resolve the problem.
        \n\n2. Individual interviews with the complainant, the respondent and any witnesses will be held. Neither the name of the employee lodging the complaint nor the circumstances related to the complaint will be revealed to any other party, unless such disclosure is necessary for the purpose of investigating or taking disciplinary action with respect to the complaint.
        \n\n3. If the investigation reveals evidence to support the complaint of workplace violence, appropriate measures will be taken. These may include disciplinary action up to and including termination.
        \n\n4. A designated investigator will summarize their findings and reach a decision on recommended action and may share these findings with additional senior management. Written results of the investigation and recommended resolution of the situation will then be presented to the two parties. If the respondent is disciplined, the incident will be documented and filed in his/her employment file in accordance with the procedures.
        \n\n5. If the investigation fails to find evidence to support the complaint, there will be no documentation file placed in the parties’ personal files.
        \n\n6. Employees who make legitimate, complaints of workplace violence in good faith will not have their employment affected in any adverse manner.
        \n\n7. Where the complaint is determined to be abusive, frivolous, vindictive, or made in bad faith, the company will take appropriate action towards the complainant, which may include termination.
        \n\n8. Reprisal against an individual who has filed a complaint in good faith or who has been named as a witness or respondent in a complaint may result in disciplinary action being taken by the company. This discipline may occur whether or not the complaint was substantiated and whether or not the complaint was resolved through any of the procedures set out in this policy</string>
    <string name="investigation_p2">\nAll information regarding a specific incident will be kept CONFIDENTIAL within the necessary boundaries of the fact-finding process.</string>
    <string name="retaliation_heading">Retaliation:</string>
    <string name="retaliation_p1">We are committed to maintaining an environment free from retaliation. Retaliation against employees for reporting such behaviour or participating in an investigation will not be tolerated by the company, and will be grounds for further disciplinary actions, up to and including termination.</string>
    <string name="reprisals_heading">Reprisals:</string>
    <string name="reprisals_p1">No employee shall be demoted, dismissed, disciplined or denied a promotion, advancement or employment opportunity or suffer a change in job responsibility because he/she has reported violence against another employee, has lodged a complaint in accordance with this policy, or has supported another employee in his/her complaint.</string>
    <string name="procedure_heading">Procedure if a Complaint is made Against an Employee:</string>
    <string name="procedure_p1">If you are accused of any type of violence, an employee must immediately inform your manager. Additionally, an employee has a duty to cooperate in the inquiry, regardless of how the employee feels about the allegations. An employee will be expected to answer questions completely and honestly. An employee may not retaliate against the person(s) who made the complaint or against anyone who participates in any way in the investigation. Retaliation will lead to disciplinary action and/ or termination of employment.</string>
    <string name="end">*This policy is subject to be amendment and/or revocation at the company’s sole discretion, without prior notice to employees.</string>
    <string name="time_off_click_here">If you would like to use your vacation day please click <font color='#01C6DB'>here.</font></string>
    <string name="prescription">• 80%</string>
    <string name="deductible">Deductible</string>
    <string name="deductible_1">• None</string>
    <string name="hospital_heading">Hospital</string>
    <string name="hospital_1">• 100% Semi-private room</string>
    <string name="paramedical_heading">Paramedical Services</string>
    <string name="paramedicl_1">• 80% reimbursement on maximum with $500.00 annually maximum per person and service.  Covered services include:</string>
    <string name="paramedical_2">\u2022 Chiropractor
        \n\u2022 Osteopath
        \n\u2022 Chiropodist
        \n\u2022 Podiatrist
        \n\u2022 Naturopath
        \n\u2022 Physiotherapist - $1,000 benefit
        \n\u2022 Psychologist or Social Worker
        \n\u2022 Speech Therapist
        \n\u2022 Occupational Therapist
        \nu2022 Acupuncturist
        \n\u2022 Dietitian
        \n\u2022 Audiologist
        \n\u2022 Massage Therapist "</string>


</resources>