<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">

    <string name="register">No account? Register <font color='#01C6DB'>here.</font></string>
    <string name="app_name">BuildingBlocksHR</string>
    <string name="open">open</string>
    <string name="close">close</string>
    <string name="bbhrBrowser">Taking you to BBRH website</string>
    <string name="helpMsg">Instructions on how to use the App go here!</string>
    <string name="OkMsg">Yes!</string>
    <string name="policy"><u>Policies      </u></string>
    <string name="compliance">Compliance Policies</string>
    <string name="violance_harassment">Viloence, Workplace and Sexual Harassment</string>
    <string name="aoda">AODA</string>
    <string name="health_safety">Health and Safety</string>
    <string name="privacy">Privacy and Personal information</string>
    <string name="other_policies">Other Policies</string>
    <string name="vacation">Vacation</string>
    <string name="benefits">Benefits</string>
    <string name="loading">Just a moment...</string>
    <string name="violence_policy_heading"><u>Violence in the Workplace Policy</u></string>
    <string name="scope_heading">Applicability and Scope</string>
    <string name="scope">This policy applies to all the company employees, including temporary employees and independent contractors.</string>

    <string name="policyIntent_heading">Policy Intent</string>
    <string name="intentp1">The company recognizes that every person is entitled to a safe work environment that is free of violence and threatening behaviour.</string>
    <string name="intentp2">The company will adhere to the spirit and intent of all applicable federal and provincial legislation governing workplace violence including, but not limited to, the Occupational Health and Safety Act, the Criminal Code, and Bill 168, etc.</string>
    <string name="intentp3">The company is committed to maintaining a workplace where all employees are treated with dignity and respect. There will be zero tolerance of any form of workplace violence or threatening behaviour toward its employees.</string>
    <string name="intentp4">Specifically, if the company is aware that domestic violence is likely to expose an employee to a workplace physical injury, every reasonable precaution will be implemented to protect the individual.</string>
    <string name="intentp5">The company will also disclose information about anyone who has a history of violent behaviour to employee(s) who may come in contact with that person.</string>
    <string name="intentp6">It is a violation of the company’s Violence in the Workplace Policy for anyone to knowingly make a false complaint of violence, or to provide false information about a complaint. Individuals who violate this Policy are subject to disciplinary and/or corrective action, up to and including termination of employment</string>
    <string name="intentp7">This policy outlines the commitment, principles and procedures that the company will follow with respect to preventing and stopping violence in the workplace.</string>
    <string name="purpose_heading">Purpose</string>
    <string name="purpose_p1">The purpose of this policy is to provide information to all employees regarding:</string>
    <string name="purpose_bullet1">• Workplace Violence
        \n• Handling Complaints </string>

    <string name="accountability_heading">Accountability</string>
    <string name="accountability_p1">The company will, in accordance with all provincial legislation and Occupational Health and Safety Act:</string>
    <string name="account_bullet1">• Appoint a Workplace Violence and Harassment Coordinator;
        \n• Assess the risk of workplace violence that may result from the nature of the company worksites and the nature and conditions of work performed there;
        \n• Establish and maintain procedures to control the risks identified in the risk assessment;
        \n• Reassess the risk of workplace violence as often as is necessary;
        \n• Take every reasonable precaution to protect employees from domestic violence that may occur in the workplace and expose employees to physical injury;
        \n• Establish measures for summoning immediate assistance when workplace violence is threatened, occurs, or is likely to occur;
        \n• Inform employees on when and how to seek medical assistance should a violent incident occur in the workplace;
        \n\u2022 Establish an investigation procedure for dealing with incidents or allegations of workplace violence or threats of violence;
        \n• Provide all employees with training and information regarding this policy and associated procedures;
        \n• Monitor the company compliance with this policy and established procedures;  </string>
    <string name="account_bullet12">• Review this policy annually to ensure that it is current and effective.</string>

    <string name="accountability_p2">Accountability for ensuring compliance with the provisions of this policy rests with Management.</string>
    <string name="account_responsibilities">Responsibilities of Employees:</string>
    <string name="responsibilities_bullet1">• Familiarize themselves with this policy;
        \n• Attend any training related to this policy;
        \n• Ask their supervisor for clarification on this policy if they have questions;
        \n• Help promote a violence-free workplace;
        \n• Refrain from workplace violence as defined in this policy; and
        \n• Immediately report to appropriate management staff incidents of, threats of, or potential for workplace violence, whether directly experienced or witnessed.</string>

    <string name="account_management">Responsibilities of Management:</string>
    <string name="management_bullet1">\u2022 Foster a violence-free workplace;
        \n• Ensure that employees receive adequate information and training on this policy;
        \n• Report any incidents or potential for workplace violence;
        \n• Investigate all aspects of any reported instances of harassment in conjunction with reporting in a timely manner;
        \n• Maintain confidentiality in the investigation process;
        \n• If a member of management becomes aware or receives knowledge that:</string>

    <string name="management_bullet6i">i.  Domestic violence may occur in the workplace that would likely expose any employee to physical injury;
        \n ii.  An employee may, in the course of their duties, encounter another employee or other person who has a history of violent behaviour, and
        \n iii.  There is a risk of workplace violence that is likely to expose the employee to physical injury.</string>

    <string name="management_responsibilities">Management will immediately advise who will provide information, including personal information, to the employee sufficient to protect them from physical injury. Personal information will only be provided that is reasonably necessary to protect the employee from physical injury.</string>
    <string name="violence_workplace_heading">Violence in the Workplace</string>
    <string name="violence_intro">Violence in the workplace involves the infliction of physical and/or mental injuries by an individual or individuals, whether employed or not employed by the company. The company prohibits any type of violence in the work environment and employees who exhibit workplace violence will be subject to disciplinary action up to and including termination of employment.</string>
    <string name="violence_def">\"Workplace violence\" means but not limited to:</string>
    <string name="violence_def_bullet1">• The exercise of physical force against an employee in a workplace that causes, or could cause, physical injury to the employee, their personal property, their family, or their friends;
        \n• An attempt to exercise physical force against an employee in a workplace that could cause physical injury to the employee, their personal property, their family, or their friends;
        \n• A statement or behaviour that is reasonable for an employee to interpret as a threat to exercise physical force against an employee, in a workplace, that causes or could cause physical injury to the employee;
        \n• Physical acts (e.g. hitting, shoving, pushing, kicking, sexual assault);
        \n• Any threat, behaviour or action which is interpreted to carry the potential to harm or endanger the safety of others, result in an act of aggression, or destroy or damage property;
        \n• Disruptive behaviour that is not appropriate to the work environment (e.g. yelling, swearing);
        \n• Any such actions which occur outside the workplace, but have repercussions in the work environment. </string>

    <string name="violence_example">Examples of workplace violence include, but are not limited to:</string>
    <string name="violence_ex_bullet1">• Allowing or engaging in violent events/behaviour and threats verbal or written or physical gestures;
        \n• Harassing phone calls, voicemails or e-mail messages;
        \n• Having/threatening with a weapon;
        \n• Offensive comments;
        \n• Physical assault.</string>

    <string name="weapons_example">Examples of Weapons include, but are not limited to:</string>
    <string name="weapons_ex_bullet1">• Dangerous chemicals other than mace or pepper spray;
       \n• Firearms;
       \n• Knives with a blade length of 3.5 inches or greater.</string>

    <string name="prevention_guidelines">The following are some general guidelines for helping to prevent violence in the workplace:</string>
    <string name="prevention_bullet1">• Do not personalize the words or actions (i.e.: don’t get defensive and don’t feed into their anger);
        \n• Stick to the issues or facts of the situation;
        \n• Be polite and professional;
        \n• Try to paraphrase the other party’s concerns back to them, to let them know that they are being heard and understood;
        \n• Do not attempt to physically touch the other party;
        \n• Report, record and investigate all incidents of violence;
        \n• If an employee has been the victim of violence in the workplace, be sure to complete and submit a report (within 24 hours of occurrence), so that this individual can receive appropriate counselling.</string>

    <string name="incident_report">In the event that an employee is either directly affected by or witness to any violence in the workplace, it is imperative for the safety of all the company employees that the incident be reported without delay.</string>
    <string name="incident_report_bullet1">• Report any violence or potentially violent situations immediately to management;
        \n• Depending on the severity of the situation, the local police may be called;
        \n• All reports shall be kept confidential;
        \n• All reports shall be investigated, and dealt with appropriately;
        \n• Any the company employee who threatens, harasses or abuses another employee, or any other individual at or from the workplace shall be subject to disciplinary action, up to and including termination of employment,
        and the pursuit of appropriate legal action;
        \n• Violent action, threats and assault are serious criminal offences, and shall be dealt with appropriately.</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step1">Step 1</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_p1">Any person who feels that he/she has experienced workplace violence or threats of such violence may request assistance or file a complaint under this policy without prejudice or fear of reprisal. If you believe that you have been threatened with or subjected to workplace violence:</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_heading">Reporting and Investigating Complaints of Violence in the Workplace</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_bullet1">• If you believe that an employee or other person with whom you interact in the course of your duties (for example, a customer, supplier, etc.) has subjected you to violence or threats of violence, report the incident to management immediately.
        \n• Keep a record of the incident(s) including dates, location, witnesses, your response to the individual and any other pertinent information.
        \n• If allegations of workplace violence are made against you, keep a record of your version of the alleged incident. If you believe the complaint is unfounded or made in bad faith, discuss the matter with management immediate.</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step2">Step 2</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step2_bullet1">• If the offensive behaviour does not stop, file a formal written complaint to management. Any formal written complaint filed by an employee must contain:</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step2_bullet1_2">• Name(s) of the respondent(s);
        \n• The date or dates of the incident(s);
        \n• Location(s) of the alleged incident(s);
        \n• Details of the incident(s); and
        \n• Names of any witnesses.</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step2_bullet2">• The issue will be addressed with the alleged offender in accordance with Step 3.</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step3">Step 3</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step3_bullet1">• The written complaint will be reviewed and may determine that an investigation is warranted and evidence indicates that violence, as defined by the policy and applicable legislation, has occurred.
        \n• Measures will be implemented immediately to protect the victim from further harm.
        \n• Confidentiality will be maintained at all times except when the disclosure of names is necessary for the purpose of investigating the complaint, when taking any action in relation to the complaint, or where disclosure is required by law.
        \n•  If criminal actions are alleged, witnessed, or found to have occurred, the appropriate member of management will contact Law enforcement agency immediately. Criminal actions include, but are not limited to, the following behaviours:</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_step3_bullet1_2">• The displaying of hate-based graffiti or pornography;
        \n\u2022 The transmission or storing of electronic telecommunications that incite hatred and violence or that constitute pornography;
        \n▪ The displaying of symbols or emblems (including clothing) that suggest racial supremacy and incite hatred and violence;
        \n▪ Stalking (persistently pursuing a particular individual although the advances are clearly unwelcome);
        \n▪ Sexual assault or threat of sexual assault;
        \n▪ Threats against an individual or their loved ones or family;
        \n▪ Extortion; and/ or
        \n▪ Physical assault or threats of physical assault.</string>
    <string name="investigating_complaints_note">Note: Whether or not a formal complaint is filed, the company or a third party may be obligated to proceed with an investigation if it appears that applicable legislation and/or the policy has been violated.</string>

    <string name="health_safety_heading">Health and Safety Policy</string>
    <string name="applicability_heading">Applicability</string>

    <string name="responsibilities_heading">Responsibilities</string>
    <string name="responsibilities_p1">All the company employees have a responsibility not to harass any other employee, contract employee, consultant, supplier, customer or visitor. Each employee in a management capacity must not allow or condone behaviour contrary to this policy and is
        responsible for ensuring that all employees under his or her supervision are aware of this policy. Any employee who fails to comply with the provisions of this policy will be subject to appropriate disciplinary measures, which may include termination.</string>
    <string name="employer_procedure_heading">Employers – Procedure for Handling Complaints</string>
    <string name="formal_investigation_heading">FORMAL INVESTIGATION PROCEDURE</string>
    <string name="investigation_p1">1. A designated investigator will undertake an investigation immediately and all necessary steps will be taken to resolve the problem.
        \n\n2. Individual interviews with the complainant, the respondent and any witnesses will be held. Neither the name of the employee lodging the complaint nor the circumstances related to the complaint will be revealed to any other party, unless such disclosure is necessary for the purpose of investigating or taking disciplinary action with respect to the complaint.
        \n\n3. If the investigation reveals evidence to support the complaint of workplace violence, appropriate measures will be taken. These may include disciplinary action up to and including termination.
        \n\n4. A designated investigator will summarize their findings and reach a decision on recommended action and may share these findings with additional senior management. Written results of the investigation and recommended resolution of the situation will then be presented to the two parties. If the respondent is disciplined, the incident will be documented and filed in his/her employment file in accordance with the procedures.
        \n\n5. If the investigation fails to find evidence to support the complaint, there will be no documentation file placed in the parties’ personal files.
        \n\n6. Employees who make legitimate, complaints of workplace violence in good faith will not have their employment affected in any adverse manner.
        \n\n7. Where the complaint is determined to be abusive, frivolous, vindictive, or made in bad faith, the company will take appropriate action towards the complainant, which may include termination.
        \n\n8. Reprisal against an individual who has filed a complaint in good faith or who has been named as a witness or respondent in a complaint may result in disciplinary action being taken by the company. This discipline may occur whether or not the complaint was substantiated and whether or not the complaint was resolved through any of the procedures set out in this policy</string>
    <string name="investigation_p2">\nAll information regarding a specific incident will be kept CONFIDENTIAL within the necessary boundaries of the fact-finding process.</string>
    <string name="retaliation_heading">Retaliation:</string>
    <string name="retaliation_p1">We are committed to maintaining an environment free from retaliation. Retaliation against employees for reporting such behaviour or participating in an investigation will not be tolerated by the company, and will be grounds for further disciplinary actions, up to and including termination.</string>
    <string name="reprisals_heading">Reprisals:</string>
    <string name="reprisals_p1">No employee shall be demoted, dismissed, disciplined or denied a promotion, advancement or employment opportunity or suffer a change in job responsibility because he/she has reported violence against another employee, has lodged a complaint in accordance with this policy, or has supported another employee in his/her complaint.</string>
    <string name="procedure_heading">Procedure if a Complaint is made Against an Employee:</string>
    <string name="procedure_p1">\nIf you are accused of any type of violence, an employee must immediately inform your manager. Additionally, an employee has a duty to cooperate in the inquiry, regardless of how the employee feels about the allegations. An employee will be expected to answer questions completely and honestly. An employee may not retaliate against the person(s) who made the complaint or against anyone who participates in any way in the investigation. Retaliation will lead to disciplinary action and/ or termination of employment.</string>
    <string name="end">\n*This policy is subject to be amendment and/or revocation at the company’s sole discretion, without prior notice to employees.</string>
    <string name="time_off_click_here">If you would like schedule time off, please click <font color='#01C6DB'>here.</font></string>

    <!-- health -->
    <string name="prescription">• 80%</string>
    <string name="deductible">Deductible</string>
    <string name="deductible_1">• None</string>
    <string name="hospital_heading">Hospital</string>
    <string name="hospital_1">• 100% Semi-private room</string>
    <string name="paramedical_heading">Paramedical Services</string>
    <string name="paramedicl_1">• 80% reimbursement on maximum with $500.00 annually maximum per person and service.  Covered services include:</string>
    <string name="paramedical_2">\u2022 Chiropractor
        \n\u2022 Osteopath
        \n\u2022 Chiropodist
        \n\u2022 Podiatrist
        \n\u2022 Naturopath
        \n\u2022 Physiotherapist - $1,000 benefit
        \n\u2022 Psychologist or Social Worker
        \n\u2022 Speech Therapist
        \n\u2022 Occupational Therapist
        \n\u2022 Acupuncturist
        \n\u2022 Dietitian
        \n\u2022 Audiologist
        \n\u2022 Massage Therapist "</string>
    <string name="orthopedic_shoes_heading">Custom made Orthopedic Shoes</string>
    <string name="orthopedic_shoe_amount">• $500.00 per calendar year</string>
    <string name="orthotic_mold_heading">Orthotic Molds</string>
    <string name="orthotic_amount">• $350.00 per calendar year</string>
    <string name="coverage_age">• Until age 70</string>
    <string name="coverage_heading">Coverage</string>
    <string name="Optometrist_amount">• $50.00 every 2 years</string>
    <string name="Optometrist_heading">Ophthalmologist or Optometrist</string>
    <string name="emergency_travel_amount">• Coverage as per Extended Health</string>
    <string name="emergency_travel_heading">Emergency Travel Assistance</string>
    <string name="hearing_aid_amount">• $500.00 every 5 years</string>
    <string name="hearing_aid_heading">Hearing Aids</string>
    <string name="medical_devices_amount">• 80%</string>
    <string name="medical_devices_heading">Medical Devices and Services</string>
    <string name="wig_amount">• $300.00</string>
    <string name="wig_heading">Wigs</string>

    <!-- dental-->
    <string name="xray_amount">• 1 every 24 months</string>
    <string name="xray_heading">X-Rays</string>
    <string name="oral_exam_amount">• 1 every 24 months</string>
    <string name="oral_exam_heading">Oral Exams</string>
    <string name="emergency_travel">• Yes</string>
    <string name="maximum_amount">• $1,00.00 per year</string>
    <string name="maximum_heading">Maximum</string>
    <string name="prevention_amount">• 2 visits per year(every 6 months)</string>
    <string name="prevention_heading">Prevention Frequency</string>
    <string name="annual_limit_amount">• 80% reimbursment (except if started half year - 50%)</string>
    <string name="annual_limit_heading">Annual Limit (Combined Basic and Major)</string>
    <string name="you_have_">You currently have  </string>
    <string name="vacation_days_remaining">vacation days.</string>

    <!-- AODA Policy-->
    <string name="aoda_heading">Accessibility Standard for Customer Service AODA Policy </string>
    <string name="aoda_p1">The Accessibility Standard for Customer Service is an Ontario regulation that applies to all people and organizations across all provinces where the company operates. "</string>
    <string name="aoda_intent_p1">The purpose of this policy is to ensure that the company is committed to excellence in serving all clients including individuals with disabilities.</string>
    <string name="regulation_heading">The Regulation</string>
    <string name="aoda_regualtion_p1">Recognizing the history of discrimination against persons with disabilities in Ontario and Canada, the purpose of the Accessibility Standard for Customer Service is to benefit everyone by:
        \n\n(a) Developing, implementing and enforcing accessibility standards in order to achieve accessibility for Ontarians with disabilities with respect to goods, services, facilities, accommodation, employment, buildings, structures and premises on or before January 1, 2012; and
        \n\n(b) Providing for the involvement of persons with disabilities, of all the Governments and of representatives of industries and of various sectors of the economy in the development of the accessibility standards. </string>

    <string name="definitions_of_the_act_heading">Definitions of the Act</string>
    <string name="disability"><i>Disability</i>
        \n\u2022   Any degree of physical disability, infirmity malformation or disfigurement that is caused by bodily injury, birth defect or illness and, without limiting the generality of the foregoing, includes diabetes mellitus, epilepsy, a brain injury, any degree of paralysis, amputation, lack of physical co-ordination, blindness or visual impediment, deafness or hearing impediment, muteness or speech impediment, or physical reliance on a guide dog or other animal or on a wheelchair or other remedial appliance or device,
        \n\u2022   A condition of mental impairment or a development disability,
        \n\u2022   A learning disability, or a dysfunction in one or more of the processes involved in understanding or using symbols or spoken language,
        \n\u2022   A mental disorder or,
        \n\u2022   An injury or disability for which benefits were claimed or received under the insurance plan established under the Workplace Safety and Insurance Act, 1997 (“handicap”). </string>
    <string name="accessibility_standard">\n<i>Accessibility Standard</i>
        \n\u2022   An accessibility standard made by regulation under section 6; (“accessibility norm”)
        \n\u2022   “Barrier” means anything that prevents a person with a disability from fully participating in all aspects of society because of his or her disability, including a physical barrier, an architectural barrier, an information or communications barrier, an attitudinal barrier, a technological barrier, a policy or a practice; (“obstacle”)</string>
    <string name="other_definitions">Other Definitions</string>
    <string name="guide_dog">\n<u>Guide Dog </u>
        \nThis is a highly-trained working dog that has been trained at a facility regulated by the government, to provide mobility, safety and increased independence for people who are blind. "</string>
    <string name="service_animal">\n<u>Service Animal</u>
        \nAn animal is a service animal for a person with a disability if:
        \n\u2022  It is readily apparent that the animal is used by the person for reasons relating to his or her disability; or
        \n\u2022  If the person provides a letter from a physician or nurse confirming that the person requires the animal for reasons relating to the disability.</string>
    <string name="service_dog">\n<u>Service Dog</u>
        \nA dog other than a guide dog for the blind is a service dog if:
        \n\u2022  It is readily apparent to an average person that the dog functions as a service dog for a person with a medical disability; or
        \n\u2022  The person who requires the dog can provide on request, a letter from a physician or nurse confirming that the person requires a service dog.</string>
    <string name="support_person">\n<u>Support Person</u>
        \nA support person means another person who accompanies a person with disability in order to help with communication, mobility, personal care, medical needs or access to goods and services.</string>
    <string name="assistive_device">\n<u>Assistive Device</u> This is a technical aid, communication device or other instrument that is used to maintain or improve the functional abilities of people with disabilities. Personal assistive devices are typically devices that customers bring with them such as a wheelchair, walker or a personal oxygen tank that might assist in hearing, seeing, communicating, moving, breathing, remembering and/or reading. "</string>
    <string name="providing_goods">Providing Goods and Services to People with Disabilities "</string>
    <string name="providing_goods_p1">Assistive Devices
        \nWe will ensure that our staff are trained and familiar with various assistive devices that may be used by customers with disabilities while accessing our goods or services.
        \n\nCommunication
        \nWe will communicate with people with disabilities in ways that take into account their disability.
        \n\nService animals
        \nWe welcome people with disabilities and their service animals. Service animals are allowed on the parts of our premises that are open to the public.
        \n\nSupport persons
        \nA person with a disability who is accompanied by a support person will be allowed to have that person accompany them on our premises. </string>
    <string name="how_to_communicate">How to Communicate with People with Different Types of Disabilities</string>
    <string name="how_to_communicate_p1">There are many types and degrees of disability. Openly communicating and responding to your customers’ needs is the key to excellent customer service for all. If you’re not sure about the best approach, just politely ask a person with a disability how you can best communicate with them.
        \n\n<u>Here are a few tips for interacting with people who have various disabilities:</u>
        \n\n<b>People with physical disabilities</b>
        \nOnly some people with physical disabilities use a wheelchair. Someone with a spinal cord injury may use crutches while someone with severe arthritis or a heart condition may have difficulty walking longer distances.
        \n\n<b>Tips: </b>
        \n\u2022  If you need to have a lengthy conversation with someone who uses a wheelchair or scooter, consider sitting so you can make eye contact at the same level.
        \n\u2022  Don’t touch items or equipment, such as canes or wheelchairs, without permission.
        \n\u2022  If you have permission to move a person’s wheelchair, don’t leave the person in an awkward, dangerous or undignified position, such as facing a wall or in the path of opening doors.
        \n\n<b>People with vision loss</b>
        \nVision loss can restrict someone’s ability to read, locate landmarks or see hazards. Some customers may use a guide dog or a white cane, while others may not.
        \n\n<b>Tips:</b>
        \n\u2022  When you know someone has vision loss, don’t assume the individual can’t see you. Many people who have low vision still have some sight.
        \n\u2022  Identify yourself when you approach and speak directly to the customer.
        \n\u2022  Ask if they would like you to read any printed material out loud to them (for example, a menu or schedule of fees).
        \n\u2022  When providing directions or instructions, be precise and descriptive.
        \n\u2022  Offer your elbow to guide them if needed.
        \n\n<b>People who have hearing loss</b>
        \nPeople who have hearing loss may be deaf, deafened or hard of hearing. They may also be oral deaf – unable to hear, but prefer to talk instead of using sign language. These terms are used to describe different levels of hearing and/or the way a person’s hearing was diminished or lost.
        \n\n<b>Tips:</b>
        \n\2022  Once a customer has identified themselves as having hearing loss, make sure you are in a well-lit area where they can see your face and read your lips.
        \n\u2022  As needed, attract the customer’s attention before speaking. Try a gentle touch on the shoulder or wave of your hand.
        \n\u2022  If your customer uses a hearing aid, reduce background noise or move to a quieter area.
        \n\u2022  If necessary, ask if another method of communicating would be easier (for example, using a pen and paper).
        \n\n<b>People who are deafblind</b>
        \nA person who is deafblind may have some degree of both hearing and vision loss. Many people who are deafblind will be accompanied by an intervener, a professional support person who helps with communication. </string>
    <string name="how_to_communicate_p2">Tips:
        \n\u2022A customer who is deafblind is likely to explain to you how to communicate with him/her, perhaps with an assistance card or a note.
        \n\u2022  Speak directly to your customer, not to the intervener.
        \n\n<b>People with speech or language impairments</b>
        \nCerebral palsy, hearing loss or other conditions may make it difficult for a person to pronounce words or may cause slurring. Some people who have severe difficulties may use a communication board or other assistive devices.
        \n\n<b>Tips:</b>
        \n\u2022  Don’t assume that a person with a speech impairment also has another disability.
        \n\u2022  Whenever possible, ask questions that can be answered with “yes” or a “no”.
        \n\u2022  Be patient. Don’t interrupt or finish your customer’s sentences.
        \n\n<b>People who have learning disabilities</b>
        \nThe term “learning disabilities” refers to a variety of disorders. One example is dyslexia, which affects how a person takes in or retains information. This disability may become apparent when a person has difficulty reading material or understanding the information you are providing.
        \n\n<b>Tips:</b>
        \n\u2022  Be patient – people with some learning disabilities may take a little longer to process information, to understand and to respond.
        \n\u2022  Try to provide information in a way that takes into account the customer’s disability. For example, some people with learning disabilities find written words difficult to understand, while others may have problems with numbers and math.
        \n\n<b>People who have intellectual / developmental disabilities/</b>
        \nDevelopmental or intellectual disabilities, such as Down Syndrome, can limit a person’s ability to learn, communicate, do every day physical activities and live independently. You may not know that someone has this disability unless you are told.
        \n\n<b>Tips:</b>
        \n\u2022  Don’t make assumptions about what a person can do.
        \n\u2022  Use plain language.
        \n\u2022  Provide one piece of information at a time.
        \n\n<b>People who have mental health disabilities</b>
        \nMental health issues can affect a person’s ability to think clearly, concentrate or remember things. Mental health disability is a broad term for many disorders that can range in severity. For example, some customers may experience anxiety due to hallucinations, mood swings, phobias or panic disorder.
        \n\n<b>Tips:</b>
        \n\u2022  If you sense or know that a customer has a mental health disability, be sure to treat them with the same respect and consideration you have for everyone else.
        \n\u2022  Be confident, calm and reassuring.
        \n\u2022  If a customer appears to be in crisis, ask them to tell you the best way to help. </string>
    <string name="how_to_interact_devices">How to interact with people who use assistive devices, and how to use any equipment that the company provides to help customers with disabilities</string>
    <string name="how_to_interact_devices_p1">The company offers equipment and assistive devices for customers with disabilities and our employees are trained to use them.  Instruction manuals and instruction sheet posted are readily available at all the company premises where devices are located or stored.
        \n\nAn assistive device is a tool, technology or other mechanism that enables a person with a disability to do everyday tasks and activities, such as moving, communicating or lifting. Personal assistive devices can include things like wheelchairs, hearing aids, white canes or speech amplification devices.
        \n\n<b>Tips: </b>
        \n\u2022  Don’t touch or handle any assistive device without permission.
        \n\u2022  Don’t move assistive devices or equipment, such as canes and walkers, out of your customers’ reach.
        \n\u2022  Let your customers know about accessible features in the immediate environment that are appropriate to their needs (e.g. public phones with TTY service, accessible washrooms, etc.).  </string>
    <string name="how_to_interact_animals">How to interact with a person who has a guide dog or other service animal</string>
    <string name="how_to_interact_animals_p1">People with vision loss may use a guide dog, but there are other types of service animals as well. Hearing alert animals help people who are deaf, deafened, oral deaf, or hard of hearing. Other service animals are trained to alert an individual to an oncoming seizure.
        \n\nUnder the standard, service animals must be allowed on the parts of your premises that are open to the public. In some instances, service animals will not be permitted in certain areas by law (for example, a restaurant kitchen).
        \n\n<b>Tips: </b>
        \n\u2022  Remember that a service animal is not a pet. It is a working animal. Avoid touching or addressing them.
        \n\u2022  If you’re not sure if the animal is a pet or a service animal, ask your customer.  </string>
    <string name="how_to_support_person">How to serve a person accompanied by a support person</string>
    <string name="how_to_support_person_p1">Some people with disabilities may be accompanied by a support person, such as an intervener. A support person can be a personal support worker, a volunteer, a family member or a friend. A support person might help a customer with a variety of things from communicating, to helping with mobility, personal care or medical needs.
        \nSupport persons are welcomed by the company and are permitted in any part of the company’s premises that are open to the public.
        \n\n<b>Tips: </b>
        \n\u2022  If you’re not sure which person is the customer, take your lead from the person using or requesting your goods or services, or simply ask.
        \n\u2022  Speak directly to your customer, not to their support person.  </string>
    <string name="how_to_assist_w_dissabilities">How to assist people with disabilities who need help accessing your goods or services</string>
    <string name="how_to_assist_w_dissabilities_p1">If you notice that your customer is having difficulty accessing your goods or services, a good starting point is to simply ask “How can I help you?”.
        \n\nYour customers are your best source for information about their needs. A solution can be simple and they will likely appreciate your attention and consideration. "</string>
    <string name="notice_of_disruption">Notice of Temporary Disruption</string>
    <string name="notice_of_disruption_p1">In the event of a planned or unexpected disruption to service or facilities for customers with disabilities, the company will notify clients promptly.
        \n\n<b>Notifications will include:</b>
        \n\u2022  Goods or services that are disrupted or unavailable
        \n\u2022  Information about the reason for the disruption \tIts anticipated length of time of disruption
        \n\u2022  A description of alternative facilities or services, if available
        \n\nAn AODA Disruption in Service Notice template should be used to prepare notice of temporary disruption (if required)
        \n\n<b>Notifications Options:</b>
        \nWhen disruptions occur, the company will provide notice by:
        \n\u2022  Posting notices in conspicuous places including at the point of disruption, at the main entrance and the nearest accessible entrance to the service disruption and/or on the company website;
        \n\u2022  Contacting customers with appointments; \tVerbally notifying customers when they are making a reservation or appointment; or
        \n\u2022  By any other method that may be reasonable under the circumstances. </string>
    <string name="staff_training">Training for Staff</string>
    <string name="staff_training_p1">The company will provide training to employees and others who deal with the public or other third parties on their behalf.
        \n\n<u>Information that will be provided: </u>
        \n\nAn overview of the Accessibility for Ontarians with Disabilities Act, 2005 and other provincial legislation as they become adopted.
        \n\u2022  The requirements of the customer service standard.
        \n\u2022  The company plan related to the customer service standard.
        \n\u2022  How to interact and communicate with people with various types of disabilities.
        \n\u2022  How to interact with people with disabilities who use an assistive device or require the assistance of a service animal or a support person.
        \n\u2022  How to use specific equipment or device, e.g. wheelchair, etc.
        \n\u2022  What to do if a person with a disability is having difficulty in accessing the company’s goods and services.
        \n\u2022  When changes are made to the company plan. </string>
    <string name="feedback">Feedback Process</string>
    <string name="feedback_p1">\u2022  Customers who wish to provide feedback on the way the company provides goods and services to people with disabilities can provide feedback through email or verbally.
        \n\u2022  All feedback will be directed to Human Resources. \tCustomers can expect to hear back within 48 business hours.
        \n\u2022  Complaints will be addressed according to our organization’s regular complaint management procedures. </string>
    <string name="mods_to_policy">Modifications to this or other policies</string>
    <string name="mods_to_policy_p1">Any policy of the company that does not respect and promote the dignity and independence of people with disabilities will be modified or removed.
        \n\nPlease contact Human Resources should you require additional information
        \n\n\n<i>*This policy is subject to be amendment and/or revocation at the company’s sole discretion, without prior notice to employees</i>\n\n\n\n</string>

<!-- HEALTH AND SAFETY POLICY -->
    <string name="health_intent_p1" tools:ignore="TypographyOther">The policy intent is to ensure that the company commitment to providing a healthy and safe work environment is communicated and understood by all employees.
        \n\nThe company (the “Company”) considers health and safety a critical priority requiring the constant attention and involvement of both management and employees. The company requires that
        all employees comply with all applicable health and safety regulations and insists that all employees respect and abide by spirit and intent of health and safety regulations.
        \n\nA healthy and safe workplace benefits both the company and its employees.  Management and employees have a shared responsibility to maintain a healthy and safe workplace.  Management is
        committed to promoting safe work practices and to taking all reasonable precautions to address workplace hazards.  Employees will accept responsibility for working in a safe manner and for
        bringing potentially hazardous conditions or practices to the attention of management.
        \n\nIt is the company’s policy to:
        \n\n(a) Strive toward eliminating workplace injuries and illnesses.
        \n(b) Have a fire safety and emergency plan in place.
        \n(c) Comply with municipal, provincial and federal health and safety legislation.</string>
    <string name="management_responsibilities_heading">Responsibilities: Management</string>
    <string name="manage_responsabilities_p1">\n1.\tEnsure that all facilities and working environments, working procedures, machinery, equipment, tools, vehicles, mobile equipment, safety materials, equipment, devices, and clothing used by employees in the course of their employment meet all legislated and prescribed safety codes and safety standards.
        \n\n2.\tProvide each employee with information, instructions, training and supervision necessary to ensure the health and safety of employees at work, as required by safety codes and safety standards.
        \n\n3.\tInvestigate, record, and report all known accidents, occupational diseases and other hazardous occurrences, take necessary remedial action, and maintain all health and safety records as required.
        \n\n4.\tProvide first-aid facilities and services, and sanitary facilities as prescribed by safety codes and safety standards.
        \n\n5.\tEnsure compliance with all fire safety and emergency measures prescribed by safety codes and safety standards.
        \n\n6.\tEnsure that every person granted access to the workplace complies with all safety requirements and is provided with and made familiar with the use of all required safety materials, devices, and clothing.
        \n\n7.\tEnsure that all hazardous substances in the workplace are controlled, handled, identified, labeled, and recorded as prescribed by the Workplace Hazardous Materials Information System legislation.
        \n\n8.\tEnsure that employees receive adequate training in their specific work tasks to protect their health and safety. </string>
    <string name="employee_responsibilities">Responsibilities: Employees</string>
    <string name="employee_responsibilities_p1">\n1.\tUse all protective safety materials, equipment, device and clothing provided by the company, as applicable.
        \n\n2.\tFollow all prescribed health and safety procedures and instructions.
        \n\n3.\tTake all reasonable and necessary precautions to ensure the health and safety of themselves and others.
        \n\n4.\tImmediately report to the supervisor/manager any item or circumstance in the workplace that is likely to be hazardous to the health and safety of themselves or others.
        \n\n5.\tImmediately notify supervisor/manager of every accident or other occurrence arising in the course of, or in connection with, the employee’s work that has caused injury to themselves or any other individual, and/or damage to company property and /or the property of others.</string>
    <string name="safety_comittee_responsibilities">Responsibilities: Health and Safety Committee Members</string>
    <string name="safety_comittee_responsibilities_p1">\n1.\tEstablish and maintain a committee comprised of required number of individuals, according to legislated requirements.
        \n\n2.\tPerform occupational health and safety inspections of the workplace to identify and manage any and all hazards to employees.
        \n\n3.\tMeet during regular working hours at least every other month to make recommendations for the correction of unsafe or unhealthy conditions and work practices
        \n\n4.\tConsider suggestions/complaints from employees on health and safety matters in order to promote health and safety activities and programs, and to conduct or assist in carrying out safety audits within the company to uncover potentially unsafe/dangerous conditions or practices.
        \n\n5.\tTo keep accurate records of all matters brought to their attention, and keep minutes of all meetings.
        \n\n6.\tPost a copy of the minutes of each meeting in a place accessible to all employees.
        \n\n7.\tPost the names and department of all members of the Health and Safety Committee.
        \n\n8.\tPost a copy of this policy, a copy of the Health and Safety Act and other material relating to the health and safety of employees in a place accessible to all employees.
        \n\n9.\tRecord and investigate all workplace accidents. </string>
    <string name="human_sources_responsibilities">Responsibilities: Human Resources</string>
    <string name="human_resources_responsibilities_p1">\n1.\tLiaise with government agencies to ensure workplace health and safety compliance.
        \n\n2.\tAct as an advisor to management on health and safety policy issues.
        \n\n3.\tCoordinate health and safety inspections and follow-up to ensure the completion of necessary corrective actions.
        \n\n4.\tDesign and develop accident / incident reports and investigation procedures and company policies and procedures on workplace health and safety issues.
        \n\n5.\tMaintain an up-to-date working knowledge of health and safety regulations as mandated locally, provincially, or federally.
        \n\n6.\tReview injury and illness trends, and identify problem areas and solutions. </string>
    <string name="accident_reporting">Accident and Incident Reporting</string>
    <string name="accident_reporting_p1">Each division will ensure that at least two employees are trained in first aid procedures.  When an employee is ill or injured, all employees share the responsibility to inform their Manager and Human Resources.
        \n\nManagers and Human Resources will adhere to the following process:
        \n\t\t\u2022\t\tProvide first aid.
        \n\t\t\u2022\t\tArrange transportation to medical treatment, if required.
        \n\t\t\u2022\t\tMake a record of the incident and first aid given.
        \n\t\t\u2022\t\tInvestigate the incident and keep a record of steps taken to correct the problems.</string>
    <string name="fire_safety">Fire Safety</string>
    <string name="fire_safety_p1">Through the Health and Safety Committee, the company will develop, where possible, a fire safety and emergency plan which will be communicated to employees.
    \n\n</string>
    <string name="policy_review"><i><b>The policy and program will be reviewed annually. Please contact Human Resources should you require additional information</b></i>\n\n\n</string>

    <!-- Privacy and Personal Information Policy -->

    <string name="privacy_heading">Privacy and Personal Information and Electronic Documents Policy</string>
    <string name="applicability_p1">These guidelines apply to all the company employees, including temporary employees.</string>
    <string name="privacy_intent_p1">The company is committed to protecting the privacy of personal information of its clients, employees, independent contractors, funders and other stakeholders.  the company corporate policy on privacy is posted on the Company website at www.motionspecialties.com.
        \n\nEmployees’ personal information remains confidential throughout their career as well as after their employment with the company ends. Employees’ information will not be collected used or disclosed except in accordance with the guidelines of federal and provincial privacy acts.  Information
        about any employee will not be released without the employee’s authorization except where required by law.
        \n\nThe company will only collect employees’ personal information where permission is provided or if there is a potential contravention of the law or breaches of agreements or other circumstances that permit us to legally collect this information under the laws of Canada.
        \n\nThis policy is to ensure that the company is complying with the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA) that outlines the protection for an employee in regards to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information </string>
    <string name="scope_of_pipeda">The Scope of the PIPEDA Act</string>
    <string name="scope_of_pipeda_p1">\n\n1.\tPIPEDA governs the collection, use and disclosure of “personal information”.
        \n<b>“Personal information”</b> is any information that identifies or can be used to identify an individual, except:
        \n\t\t\u2022\tName
        \n\t\t\u2022\tBusiness address, and
        \n\t\t\u2022\tPosition within an organization
        \n\n2.\tPIPEDA applies to every (private sector) <u>organization</u>, which collects, uses or discloses personal information <u>in the course of commercial activities (with intent to generate profits).</u></string>
    <string name="principles_of_pipeda">Principles of PIPEDA</string>
    <string name="principles_of_pipedat_p1">\n1.\tInformed consent is required for the collection, use and/or disclosure of personal information, unless an exception applies:
        \n\t\t\u2022\tConsent must be explicit for sensitive information
        \n\t\t\u2022\tImplicit consent may be given for less sensitive information
        \n\n<i>Exceptions to Consent </i>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tIf it is clearly in the individual’s interests and consent is not available in a timely way
        \n\t\t\u2022\tIf knowledge and consent would compromise the availability or accuracy of the information and collection is required to investigate a breach of an agreement or contravention of a law
        \n\t\t\u2022\tIf it is publicly available as specified in the regulations
        \n\n2.\tProper purpose is required for the collection, use and/or disclosure of personal information, even without <u>consent</u>.
        \n\nA “proper purpose” must be:
        \n\t\t\u2022\tPurpose(s) to which the individual consented
        \n\t\t\u2022\tAny purpose that a reasonable person would consider appropriate in the circumstances
        \n\t\t\u2022\tJustifiable \tMinimally intrusive
        \n\nThere are no exceptions to the requirements for a proper purpose.
        \n\n3.\tRetain personal information only for as long as it is necessary to fulfill the purpose. </string>
    <string name="employer_obligations">Employer Obligations</string>
    <string name="employer_obligations_p1">An employer’s obligations are to:
        \n\t\t\u2022\tDesignate a responsible individual to act as the officer of personal information
        \n\t\t\u2022\tHave custody and control on all personal information
        \n\t\t\u2022\ttProvide security safeguards i.e.: lock on office door, locks for filing cabinet, lock on computer
        \n\t\t\u2022\tIdentify the purpose for obtaining personal information
        \n\t\t\u2022\tLimit as necessary for agreed upon purposes \tObtain employee consent to obtain personal information
        \n\t\t\u2022\ttObtain written consent for the collection, use and disclosure of any personal health information
        \n\t\t\u2022\tOnly use personal information for the purposes for which it was originally collected, except with consent or if required by law
        \n\t\t\u2022\tEnsure personal information is accurate, complete and up-to date
        \n\t\t\u2022\tProvide employees access to their personal information, if requested, and correct any incorrect information </string>
    <string name="employee_rights">Employee Rights</string>
    <string name="employee_rights_p1">\n\t\t\u2022\tProvide or withhold consent
        \n\t\t\u2022\tBe given sufficient information on how information will be disclosed
        \n\t\t\u2022\tTo know their rights
        \n\t\t\u2022\tTo have access to their information
        \n\t\t\u2022\tTo challenge the accuracy and completeness of personal information </string>
    <string name="access_to_info">Access Rights to Personal Information</string>
    <string name="access_to_info_p1">\n<b>Employers</b>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tRespond to an individual’s request within a reasonable time and at minimal or no cost to the individual
        \n\t\t\u2022\tInformation shall be provided or made available to the employee in a form that is generally understandable, for example: if the organization uses abbreviations or codes to record information, an explanation should be provided
        \n\t\t<u>Exceptions:</u>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tReasons for denying access should be provided to the individual upon request
        \n\t\t<u>Exceptions may include: </u>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tInformation that is prohibitively costly to provide \tInformation that refers to other people
        \n\t\t\u2022\tInformation that cannot be disclosed for legal, security, or commercial proprietary reasons
        \n\t\t\u2022\tInformation that is subject to solicitor-client or litigation privilege
        \n\n<b>Employees </b>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tShould be told about existence, use and disclosure of personal information
        \n\t\t\u2022\tShall be given access to that information
        \n\t\t\u2022\tCan challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it changed "</string>
    <string name="right_of_correction">Right of Correction to Personal Information</string>
    <string name="right_of_correction_p1">\n<b>Employee</b>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tMust successfully demonstrate the inaccuracy or incompleteness of personal information
        \n\n<b>Employer</b>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tShall amend the information as required
        \n\t\t\u2022\tWhere appropriate, shall transmit information to third parties having access to the information in question
        \n\n<b>Information Management</b>  Organizations are also required to produce a public statement informing the public of:
        \n\t\t\u2022\tThe types of information collected, used and disclosed and why \tExplanation of company’s privacy policies and procedures including access process
        \n\t\t\u2022\tInformation made available to related companies
        \n\t\t\u2022\tSecurity measures in place to safeguard information
        \n\t\t\u2022\tContact name of Chief Privacy Officer (documented on the company website)</string>
    <string name="personal_info">Personal Information</string>
    <string name="personal_info_p1">\nPersonal information <b>includes:</b>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tPersonal health information (which will only be collected for workers compensation and disability cases.  <b>This information will be collected and maintained by the Privacy Officer – Human Resources)</b>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tInformation that relates to the work performance of the individual
        \n\t\t\u2022\tInformation about professional wrongdoing, misconduct, or disciplinary matters
        \n\nPersonal information could also likely include (but is not limited to):
        \n\t\t\u2022\tAge
        \n\t\t\u2022\tWeight
        \n\t\t\u2022\tHeight
        \n\t\t\u2022\tMedical records
        \n\t\t\u2022\tIdentification numbers
        \n\t\t\u2022\tIncome
        \n\t\t\u2022\tEthnic origin
        \n\t\t\u2022\tBlood type
        \n\t\t\u2022\tOpinions, evaluations, comments, social status or disciplinary action
        \n\t\t\u2022\tEmployee files
        \n\t\t\u2022\tCredit records
        \n\t\t\u2022\tLoan records
        \n\nPersonal information <b>excludes:</b>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tName, title and employee’s contact information at Motion Specialties
        \n\n<b><u>Employee Client Personal Information </u></b>
        \n\t\t\u2022\tEmployee personal information that is provided to the company as data collection from a client is also protected under PIPEDA.\n\n  </string>
    <string name="please_contact_hr">\n<b>Please contact Human Resources should you require additional information.\n\n\n</b></string>

    <!-- Harassment policy -->
    <string name="sexual_harassment_heading">Workplace Harassment Policy</string>
    <string name="scope_applicable">The policy is applicable whenever an employee or independent contractor:</string>
    <string name="p1bullet1">\u2022,Carries out duties or conducts business on behalf of the company;
        \n• Represents the company on committees or at work related events/conferences
        \n• Attends work-related and industry functions; and/or
        \n• Socializes with other employees.</string>

    <string name="scope_location"> Locations and situations covered by this policy include, but are not limited to:</string>
    <string name="location_bullet1">• the company offices and worksites;
        \n• Other buildings or premises under the jurisdiction of the company;
        \n• Company vehicles;
        \n• Social functions sanctioned by or under the jurisdiction of the company whether held at company offices or facilities or at other locations approved by the company;
        \n• Work-related travel outside of company facilities;
        \n• Incidents which occur outside the workplace, but have negative repercussions at work or adversely affect working relationships;
        \n• Harassment that occurs by electronic means (e-mail, telephone, voice mail, internet, or fax) or written communication; and
        \n• Any other locations or events where company business, operations, or social functions are carried out.</string>
    <string name="intent_p1">The company recognizes that every person possesses basic human rights including the right to respect, dignity, and protection from all forms of harassment.
        \n\nThe company will adhere to the spirit and intent of all applicable provincial legislation governing workplace harassment including, but not limited to, the Ontario Human Rights Code and the Occupational Health and Safety Act.
        \n\nThe company is committed to maintaining a safe workplace where all employees are treated with dignity and respect and will have zero tolerance of any form of harassment towards its employees.
        \n\nEvery employee has a right to freedom from:
        \n\n1.\tHarassment in the workplace by the employer or agent of the employer or by another employee because of race, ancestry, place of origin, colour, ethnic origin, citizenship, creed, age, record of offences for which a pardon has been granted and not revoked, marital status, family status or disability, religion, sexual orientation, etc.
        \n\n2.\tA sexual solicitation or advance made by a person in a position to confer, grant or deny a benefit or advancement to the person where the person making the solicitation or advance knows or ought reasonably to know that it is unwelcome.
        \n\n3.\tA reprisal or a threat of reprisal for the rejection of a sexual solicitation or advance where the reprisal is made or threatened by a person in a position to confer, grant or deny a benefit or advancement to the person.
        \n\nIt is also a violation of the policy for anyone to knowingly make a false complaint of harassment or to provide false information about a complaint. Individuals who violate this policy are subject to disciplinary and/or corrective action, up to and including termination of employment.
        \n\nThis policy outlines the commitment, principles and procedures that the company will follow with respect to preventing and stopping harassment in the workplace. Any violation of this policy will be subject to disciplinary action up to, and including termination.  </string>
    <string name="harass_purpose_p1">The purpose of this policy is to provide information to all employees regarding:
        \n\t▪  Workplace Harassment
        \n\t▪  Sexual Harassment
        \n\t▪  The steps an employee should take if they feel they are being harassed or if being accused of harassment  </string>
    <string name="harass_accountibility_p1">The company will:
        \n\t▪  Appoint a Workplace Violence and Harassment Coordinator;
        \n\t▪  Establish procedures to effectively address and investigate alleged instances of workplace harassment;
        \n\t▪  Provide all employees with training and information regarding this policy;
        \n\t▪  Monitor the company\'s compliance with this policy and related procedures;
        \n\t▪  Review this policy annually to ensure that it is current and effective;
        \n\nAccountability for ensuring compliance with the provisions of this policy rest management.
        \n\nAll employees are expected to:
        \n\t▪  Familiarize themselves with this policy;
        \n\t▪  Attend any training related to this policy;
        \n\t▪  Ask their supervisor for clarification on this policy if they have questions;
        \n\t▪  Help promote a harassment-free workplace;
        \n\t▪  Refrain from workplace harassment as defined in this policy; and
        \n\t▪  Immediately report instances of actual or potential workplace harassment, whether directly experienced or witnessed, to appropriate management staff.
        \n\nIt is the responsibility of management to:
        \n\t▪  Foster a harassment-free workplace;
        \n\t▪  Model respectful behaviour in the workplace;
        \n\t▪  Ensure that employees receive adequate information and training on this policy;
        \n\t▪  Report any incidents or potential for harassment to management;
        \n\t▪  Investigate all aspects of any reported instances of harassment in a timely manner; and
        \n\t▪  Maintain confidentiality in the investigation process.   </string>
    <string name="workplace_harassment">Workplace Harassment</string>
    <string name="workplace_harassment_p1">The purpose of this policy is to encourage an efficient, productive and creative environment.  The company does not condone, nor will tolerate, verbal or physical conduct by employees or others which harasses, disrupts or interferes with work performance, creates an intimidating, offensive or hostile environment. Any breach of this policy will result in disciplinary action up to and including termination of employment.
        \n\n<i>Definition</i>
        \nThe Ontario Human Rights Code defines harassment as offending or humiliating someone physically or verbally; threatening or intimidating someone; or making unwelcome jokes or comments about  someone’s race, national or ethnic origin, colour, religion, age, sex, sexual orientation, marital status, family status, disability or pardoned conviction.
        \n\n\t▪  This also includes comments or actions in the workplace which negatively affect working relationships or productivity or create a poisoned work environment.
        \n\t▪  Engaging in a course of vexatious comment or conduct against a worker in a workplace that is known or ought reasonably to be known to be unwelcome.
        \n\t▪  Workplace harassment may include bullying, teasing, intimidating or offensive jokes or innuendos, displaying or circulating offensive pictures or materials, or offensive or intimidating phone calls.
        \n\nAlso, harassment is based on any comment or conduct, which is motivated by or reflects a prohibited ground of discrimination such as:
        \n\t▪  Race
        \n\t▪  Gender
        \n\t▪  Creed/religion
        \n\t▪  National/ethnic/social/origin
        \n\t▪  Ancestry, place of origin
        \n\t▪  Colour
        \n\t▪  Nationality/citizenship
        \n\t▪  Sexual orientation
        \n\t▪  Age
        \n\t▪  Record of offences
        \n\t▪  Marital status/family status
        \n\t▪  Disability (mental or physical, including AIDS)  ▪\tPregnancy
        \n\t▪  Political beliefs
        \n\t▪  Source of income
        \n\t▪  Written or verbal abuse
        \n\t▪  Unwelcome remarks, practical jokes which cause awkwardness or embarrassment, innuendos or taunting about a person’s body, and attire
        \n\t▪  Reasons otherwise protected by applicable laws in the province
        \n\t▪  Reprisal as defined by this policy
        \n\nThe company encourages any employee with concerns, or wishing to register complaints of unfair treatment or harassment to contact management.  </string>
    <string name="sexual_harassment">Sexual Harassment</string>
    <string name="sexual_harassment_p1"><i>Definition</i>
        \nSexual harassment encompasses a wide range of unwanted behaviour and has been defined in the following manner: Unwelcome and or repeated sexual advances, requests for sexual favours, and other verbal or physical conduct of a sexual or gender related nature may constitute sexual harassment when:
        \n\t▪  Such conduct has the purpose or effect of unreasonably interfering with an individual’s work performance or creating an intimidating, hostile, or offensive uncomfortable working environment for any employee, vendor, customer, client or visitor.
        \n\t▪  Submission to such conduct is made either explicitly or implicitly a term or condition of an individual’s employment.
        \n\t▪  Submission to or rejection of such conduct by an individual is used as the basis for employment decisions affecting such individual.
        \n\nSexual Harassment includes both verbal and/or physical conduct, and some examples may include (but not limited to):
        \n\t▪  Inappropriate physical contact such as touching, patting, kissing, etc.
        \n\t▪  Leering, staring, obscene or offensive gestures
        \n\t▪  Sexually suggestive jokes, offensive remarks or innuendoes, whether or not directed to anyone in particular
        \n\t▪  Inappropriate suggestive comments or taunting with respect to personal or physical appearance, attractiveness or unattractiveness
        \n\t▪  Displaying, posting or distributing materials such as sexually explicit posters, e-mails, calendars, cartoons, or graffiti, which are of a sexual nature
        \n\t▪  Demands for sexual favours by a colleague, supervisor or member of management
        \n\t▪  Advances of a sexual nature
        \n\t▪  Crude or suggestive comments regarding an employee’s personal life
        \n\t▪  Written or verbal threats or abuse with sexual overtones
        \n\t▪  Sexual assault
        \n\t▪  Condescension or paternalism which undermines self-respect
        \n\nIt is the company policy to maintain a work environment that is free of harassment for all employees. The company does not condone, nor will tolerate sexual harassment. Sexual harassment is unacceptable conduct, which violates this policy and is grounds for immediate termination.
        \n\nAny employee who is found to have engaged in conduct that is contrary to this policy will be subject to discipline including termination of employment and recourse to legal remedies.  </string>
    <string name="reporting_complaints">Reporting and Investigating Complaints of Sexual Harassment, Workplace Harassment and Violence in the Workplace  </string>
    <string name="reporting_complaints_p1">Any person who feels that he/she has experienced workplace harassment may take the necessary steps, file a complaint under this policy, or initiate proceedings, without prejudice or fear of reprisal. If you believe that you have been subjected to workplace harassment:
        \n\n\tStep 1
        \n\t▪  Ask the person to stop.  Do so as soon as you experience any form of unwelcome comment or conduct.  Although this may be difficult to do, telling the person that you do not like their actions is often enough to stop the behaviour.  Remind the person that the conduct is against the company policy.  If you are not comfortable with approaching the person go to Step 3.
        \n\n\t▪  If you believe that someone who is not an employee, e.g. a customer, supplier, etc., has subjected you to harassment, please report the incident to management immediately. Harassing behaviour from non-employees is not acceptable and will be dealt with under this policy.
        \n\n\tStep 2
        \n\t▪  Keep a record of the incident(s) including dates, location, witnesses, your response to the individual and any other pertinent information.
        \n\n\t▪  If allegations of workplace harassment or violence are made against you, keep a record of your version of the alleged incident.  If you believe the complaint is unfounded or made in bad faith, discuss the matter with management.
        \n\n\tStep 3
        \n\t▪  If the violent or harassing behaviour does not stop, bring the complaint immediately to the attention of management. Any formal written complaint filed by an employee must contain:
        \n\n\t▪  name(s) of the respondent(s) to the complaint;
        \n\t▪  the date or dates of the incident(s);
        \n\t▪  location(s) of the incident(s);
        \n\t▪  details of the incident(s);
        \n\t▪  names of any witnesses.
        \n\nThe issue will then be addressed with the alleged offender in accordance with Step 4.
        \n\n\tStep 4
        \n\t▪  Management will review the written complaint and may determine that an investigation is warranted if there is sufficient prima facie evidence to indicate that harassment has occurred.  Effective temporary measures will be implemented to protect the victim, if necessary.  A third party may be involved.
        \n\n\t▪  The complainant will be advised that the respondent has a right to know who is making allegations against him/her and will be provided with a copy of the written complaint for their response.
        \n\n\t▪  Confidentiality will be maintained at all times except where the disclosure of names is necessary for the purpose of investigating the complaint, when taking any action in relation to the complaint, or where disclosure is required by law.
        \n\n\t▪  If criminal actions are alleged, witnessed, or found to have occurred, the responding member of management will contact the Police immediately. Criminal actions include, but are not limited to, the following behaviours:
        \n\n\t▪  The displaying of hate-based graffiti or pornography;
        \n\n\t▪  The transmission or storing of electronic telecommunications that incite hatred and violence or that constitute pornography;
        \n\n\t▪  The displaying of symbols or emblems (including clothing) that suggest racial supremacy and incite hatred and violence;
        \n\n\t▪  Stalking (persistently pursuing a particular individual although the advances are clearly unwelcome);
        \n\n\t▪  Sexual assault or threat of sexual assault;
        \n\n\t▪  Threats against an individual or their loved ones or family;
        \n\n\t▪  Extortion; and/or
        \n\n\t▪  Physical assault or threats of physical assault.
        \n\n<i>Note:
            \nWhether or not a formal complaint is filed, Management or a third party may be obligated to proceed with an investigation if it appears that applicable legislation and/or the policy has been violated. </i> </string>
    <string name="complaints_procedure">Employers - Procedure for Handling Complaints </string>
    <string name="complaints_procedure_p1">\nFORMAL INVESTIGATION PROCEDURE
        \n\t1.  Management or a designated investigator will undertake an investigation immediately and all necessary steps will be taken to resolve the problem.
        \n\n\t2.  Individual interviews with the complainant, the respondent and any witnesses will be held. Neither the name of the employee lodging the complaint nor the circumstances related to the complaint will be revealed to any other party, unless such disclosure is necessary for the purpose of investigating or taking disciplinary action with respect to the complaint.
        \n\n\t3.  If the investigation reveals evidence to support the complaint of workplace violence, appropriate measures will be taken. These may include disciplinary action up to and including termination.
        \n\n\t4.  Management or a designated investigator will summarize their findings and reach a decision on recommended action and may share these findings with additional senior management.  Written results of the investigation and recommended resolution of the situation will then be presented to the two parties. If the respondent is disciplined, the incident will be documented and filed in his/her employment file in accordance with documentation procedures.
        \n\n\t5.  If the investigation fails to find evidence to support the complaint, there will be no documentation file placed in the parties’ personal Human Resource files.
        \n\n\t6.  Employees who make legitimate, complaints of workplace violence in good faith will not have their employment affected in any adverse manner.
        \n\n\t7.  Where the complaint is determined to be abusive, frivolous, vindictive, or made in bad faith, the company will take appropriate action towards the complainant, which may include discipline.
        \n\n\t8.  Reprisal against an individual who has filed a complaint in good faith or who has been named as a witness or respondent in a complaint may result in disciplinary action being taken by the company. This discipline may occur whether or not the complaint was substantiated and whether or not the complaint was resolved through any of the procedures set out in this policy.
        \n\nAll information regarding a specific incident will be kept CONFIDENTIAL within the necessary boundaries of the fact-finding process.
        \n\nRetaliation:
        \nWe are committed to maintaining an environment free from retaliation.  Retaliation against employees for reporting such behaviour or participating in an investigation will not be tolerated by the company, and will be grounds for further disciplinary actions, up to and including termination.
        \n\nReprisals:
        \nNo employee shall be demoted, dismissed, disciplined or denied a promotion, advancement or employment opportunity or suffer a change in job responsibility because he/she has rejected harassment of another employee, has lodged a complaint in accordance with this policy, or has supported another employee in his/her complaint.
        \n\n<u>Procedure if a Complaint is made Against an Employee</u>
        \nIf you are accused of any type of harassment, an employee must immediately inform your manager or Human Resources.  Additionally, an employee has a duty to cooperate in the inquiry, regardless of how the employee feels about the allegations.  An employee will be expected to answer questions completely and honestly.  An employee may not retaliate against the person(s) who made the complaint or against anyone who participates in any way in the investigation.
        Retaliation will lead to corrective action and/ or termination of employment. \n   </string>
    <string name="this_policy_subject_to"><i>\n*This policy is subject to be amendment and/or revocation at the Company\'s sole discretion, without prior notice to employees.\n\n</i>  </string>

   <!-- vacation policy -->
    <string name="applicability">This policy applies to all employees. </string>
    <string name="vacation_intent_p1">The purpose of this policy is to define the guidelines for vacation for the company.
        \n\nThe company deems vacation as very important!  The company recognizes that you need time away from work for rest and recreation and to regenerate to work effectively throughout the year.  Therefore, we encourage all employees to take time away from work by taking their vacation.
        \n\nThe following is an outline of the vacation guidelines and entitlement:  </string>
    <string name="eligibility_heading">Eligibility</string>
    <string name="eligibility_p1">\n\u2022\tAll regular full-time and part-time employees are eligible for vacation
        \n\u2022\tFull-time, permanent employees are eligible to receive vacation time off with pay if salaried and full-time and part-time hourly employees are eligible to receive payment equivalent to 4% of their earnings on account of their vacation entitlement.
        \n\u2022\tEmployees or individuals whose status changes from temporary/contract to permanent will be eligible for a prorated vacation accrual commencing on the first day of their new permanent status. </string>
    <string name="vacation_year_heading">Vacation Year</string>
    <string name="vacation_year_p1">\n\u2022\tThe vacation year runs from January 1 to December 31 of each year. </string>
    <string name="entitlement_heading">Vacation Entitlement for Temporary Employees</string>
    <string name="entitlement_p1">\n\u2022\tTemporary employees are not eligible for vacation time.  Temporary employees will receive vacation pay equal to 4% of the employee’s wages earned on each pay (this only applies to temporary employees on the company payroll).</string>
    <string name="entitlement_guidelines">Vacation Entitlement Guidelines</string>
    <string name="entitlement_guidelines_p1">\n\u2022\tVacation is pro-rated depending on your start of date with the company (full-time employees only).
        \n\u2022\tVacation entitlement may be different if agreed upon in writing at time of hire or per provincial requirements.
        \n\u2022\tAll hourly part-time employee’s vacation will be paid on each pay.
        \n\u2022\tAn employee may not take vacation during the probation period unless authorized.
        \n\u2022\tIn the year that the employee’s vacation entitlement increases, the vacation allotment will be prorated from your hire date. (full-time employees only)
        \n\u2022\tIn the year that the employee’s vacation entitlement increases, the vacation pay percentage increase will be effective on the anniversary of the employee’s hire date
        \n\u2022\tBy law, the company is only liable to pay the vacation entitlement according to the employment legislation governed by each Province.  Unless authorization is given by the employer to an employee for carry-over of unused vacation entitlement, the employee will lose unused vacation as long as the company has satisfied the employment law requirements.
        \n\u2022\tAll paid time must be used before unpaid time is granted. </string>
    <string name="entitlement_schedule">Vacation Entitlement Schedule in Days (Full-time):</string>
    <string name="entitlement_sched_service"><b>Service</b>
        \n\n\n1 yr &amp; less then 5 yrs
        \n5 yrs &amp; less than 10 yrs
        \n\n10 yrs &amp; less than 15 yrs
        \n\n15 yrs &amp; over\n</string>
    <string name="entitlement_sched_ent"><b>Entitlement</b> \n\n\n10 days (2 weeks) \n\n15 days ( 3 weeks) \n\n20days (4 weeks) \n\n25 days (5 weeks)\n</string>
    <string name="entitlement_sched_monthly"><b>Monthly Rate of Earning Entitlement</b> \n\n0.83 days per month\n\n1.25 days per month \n\n1.67 days per month\n\n2.08 days per month\n</string>
    <string name="entitlement_percent">Vacation Entitlement Schedule in Percent (Hourly-Part-time):</string>
    <string name="entitlement_percent_service"><b>Service</b> \n\n\n1 yr &amp; less then 5 yrs
        \n5 yrs &amp; less than 10 yrs
        \n10 yrs &amp; over\n</string>
    <string name="entitlement_percent_ent"><b>Entitlement</b> \n\n\n4% (2weeks)\n6% (3 weeks) \n\n 8% (4 weeks)\n</string>
    <string name="entitlement_percent_monthly"><b>Monthly Rate of Earning Entitlement</b>\n\n.083 days per month\n1.25 days per month\n\n1.67 days per month\n</string>
    <string name="vacation_carry_over">Vacation Carry Over  </string>
    <string name="vacation_carry_over_p1">\n\u2022\tEmployees are encouraged to take their vacation entitlement within the calendar year.
        \n\u2022\tCarry-over vacation requests must be submitted by December 1st of each year for approval.
        \n\u2022\tAn employee may carry over a maximum of 5 vacation days (for work related circumstances) into the next calendar year with approval from both the Regional VP and the VP, Human Resources via email.
        \n\u2022\tAny vacation from the previous calendar year will only be carried over to March 31st of the current year.
        \n\u2022\tAny previous year’s vacation not taken by March 31st will be forfeited.
        \n\u2022\tSpecial circumstances may arise that will allow an employee to extend the previous years’ vacation beyond March 31stwith the approval of the employee’s manager and/or Human Resources. </string>
    <string name="hourly_part_time">Hourly Employees – Part-time</string>
    <string name="hourly_part_time_p1">\n\u2022\tVacation for all hourly employees cannot be accumulated and will be paid on each pay period.</string>
    <string name="vacation_request"> Vacation Request Procedure </string>
    <string name="vacation_request_p1">To ensure that vacation records are current and up-to-date, follow these steps to request vacation:
        \n\u2022\tRequest vacation through manager
        \n\u2022\tYour manager will review/approve your request  </string>
    <string name="maternity_leave">Maternity/Parental Leave and Vacation Entitlement</string>
    <string name="maternity_leave_p1">\n\u2022\tVacation pay is not accrued for part-time employees on Leave
        \n\u2022\tFull-time permanent employees on Maternity/Parental Leave are entitled to accrue vacation time.
        \n\u2022\tAny unused vacation prior to commencing the Maternity/Parental Leave must be used before the leave or before the employee’s return from the leave. </string>
    <string name="termination_payout">Vacation Pay upon Termination of Employment</string>
    <string name="termination_payout_p1">\n\u2022\tEmployees who resign or are terminated will be paid unused vacation days on a pro-rata basis.
        \n\u2022\tAny unearned vacation used by the employee prior to the resignation or termination will be deducted from the employee’s pay.
        \n\u2022\tUnused vacation - will be paid out on the employee’s final paycheque upon termination of employment.\n\n </string>
    <string name="contact">\nPlease contact Human Resources should you require additional information.\n\n</string>
    <string name="hrHelpTitle">test test</string>
    <string name="loggingOut">loggin out...</string>


</resources>